南极洲
1904年10月10日
异形 大战 铁血战士
2004年10月3日
低地球轨道
韦兰德公司 PS12 人造卫星
“银箔”卫星接收站
内布拉斯加州
韦兰德工业
卫星跟踪与数据传送
地面接收站 #6-D
不明热源信号
过来  看看这个
Come here. Take a look at this.
不明热源信号
这是什么?
What is it?
PS12送回的数据流
- It's a data stream from PS12.
卫星在哪儿?
- Where is she?
14区正上方
- Right above sector 14.
14区什么都没有
There isn't anything in sector 14.
现在有了
There is now.
罗拉冰瀑
尼泊尔
-喂? -伍兹小姐
- Hello? - Miss Woods.
很高兴能够联络到你
Pleasure to make your acquaintance.
你是谁?
- Who is this?
我叫麦克斯韦·斯塔福德 韦兰德工业的代表
- My name's Maxwell Stafford. I represent Weyland Industries.
我猜猜看  他又要起诉我们?
- Let me guess. He's suing us again?
你误会了
- You misunderstand.
要是你愿意见见韦兰德先生
Mr Weyland has offered to fund your foundation
他会提供你们整年的支助基金
for a year, if you'll meet with him.
什么时候? 明天
When? Tomorrow.
明天可能有点问题  我回去要一个礼拜时间
Tomorrow's gonna be a problem.Take me a week to get back to the world.
不错  我曾向韦兰德先生提及这一点
Yes, I told Mr Weyland that.
他说他等不了一个礼拜
He said he didn't have a week.
特奥蒂瓦坎城
墨西哥
我们必须进去看看
We must be right on top of it.
是什么  塞巴斯提安?
What is it, Sebastian?
我要说  1950年代初期
Early 1950s, I'd say.
嗨  我们都在这里了
Hey, Juan, we're almost there!
根据你说的?给他们垂死国王的最后礼物?
According to you, the Teotihuacans' final gift to their dying king...
是一个百事可乐?
was a Pepsi.
-拜托  再给我一个月。 -不可以。
- Come on, give me one more month. - No.
-拜托了  -我要换一组人来
- Please. - I'm bringing another team.
什么?
What?
我也知道  然而缺少人手和批准  我们也束手无策
Without a crew and a permit we're out of business.
好  让小组等上两天
Hold the team together for two days.
我要去墨西哥城和银行谈谈
I'll go to Mexico City and I'll talk to the bank.
我要筹集更多的资金
I'll get us more money.
或许我能帮你达成心愿  教授
I might be able to help you accomplish that, Professor.
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
换你一小会儿时间
In exchange for a little of your time.
罗斯冰架
南极洲
查尔斯·比绍普·韦兰德  现代机器人技术先驱
噢  抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我应该把闪光灯关掉
I should've switched the flash off.
这是你的杂志
There's your magazine.
-抱歉 -不要紧
Excuse me. That's OK.
我把旅程拍回去给我的儿子看看  这就是他们
I'm documenting the trip for my boys. This is them.
雅各布和斯科提
Jacob and Scotty.
你介意替我拍张照吗?谢谢
Would you mind taking a picture? Thank you.
只是想让他们看看  老爸并不总是那么烦人
Just wanna show them that their dad wasn't always so boring.
-笑 -好
- Smile. - OK.
-好了 -谢谢
- There you go. - Thank you.
我叫格瑞米·米勒  我是化学工程师
I'm Graeme Miller.I'm a chemical engineer.
艾里莎·伍兹  环保科学技术员兼向导
Alexa Woods, environmental technician and guide.
你为韦兰德工作?
- Do you work for Weyland?
噢  不
- Oh, no.
不…我的时间都用在小型环保工作组
No, I split my time between working for a small environmental group
…以及带领科学家们在冰川上探险上
and taking scientists on expeditions on the ice.
艾里莎  系好安全带  我们要撞上气流了
Lex. Buckle up. We're gonna hit some turbulence.
谢谢  杰克
Thanks, Jack.
他是你朋友?
- Is he a friend of yours?
我爸爸的朋友 这儿大多数飞行员都是我父亲培训出来的
- Of my dad's. He trained most of the pilots here.
刚刚通过PSR
- Just passed the PSR.
噢  见鬼  我本应拍张照的
- Oh, damn. I wish I'd got a picture.
-拍什么? -PSR
- Of what? - The PSR.
我们通过之前  他就应该提醒一下
I wish he'd called it out before we passed it.
PSR是指安全返回点
The PSR is the point of safe return.
就是说我们耗尽了一半的燃料  便无法返回了
It means we've used up half our fuel, so we can't turn back.
不错  但如果情况不妙
Right, but if something went wrong,
大概我们能着陆的
we could land, presumably.
-我们可以水上迫降 -是的  水上迫降
- We could ditch. - Yeah. Ditch.
但在这种水温下我们活不过三分钟
But the temperature of the water would kill us in three minutes.
破冰船——风笛丸号
当前航向：机密
-检查完毕 -很好
- Weyland's check cleared. - Good.
你知道什么?我们正准备去听听他到底要说什么
You know what? We're gonna listen to whatever he has to say.
我们点头  微笑  无论他出任何价我们都婉拒
We nod, we smile and we politely decline whatever offer he makes.
拿着钱  我们调头回墨西哥
Take the money and we'll head back to Mexico.
好的
Right.
开心么?
Havin' fun?
是呀 真是个棒极了的冒险
Yeah! This is quite an adventure!
听着  我的孩子们不会相信这个…
Listen, my kids are not gonna to believe this...
但是你能拍个照么?
but would you make a picture?
你一直按着等闪光灯亮
You have to hold like that until it flashes.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
快下来 你把屁股当帽子戴了
Get off! Or you'll be wearing your ass for a hat!
好的。好
Alright. OK. Sure.
不错的团队精神啊
Nice team spirit.
和“偷窥者”保持距离
Keep the beakers away from the gear.
他说的“偷窥者”是什么意思?
What does he mean - 'beaker'?
就是科学家  在这里
It's what they call scientists up here.
你知道么  “挑选者”就像一场木偶戏
You know "beaker", like in the muppet show.
欢迎大家搭乘  请
Everybody. Please, your attention.
韦兰德先生
Mr Weyland.
七天前
Seven days ago,
我们在南极洲上空的一颗搜寻矿床的卫星
one of my satellites over Antarctica hunting for mineral deposits
发现了一个突然的地下热量激增
discovered a sudden heat bloom beneath the earth,
轮廓大致如此
which outlined this.
红线代表固态墙
The red lines indicate solid walls.
通过热导制图
Through thermal mapping,
我们生成了建筑物的三维影像
we've generated a three-dimensional image of the structure.
非常宏伟  包含数百个房间
It's massive, containing hundreds of rooms,
环绕着中央核心
all built around a central core.
我的专家告诉我  这是座金字塔
My experts tell me it's a pyramid.
他们无法达成共识的是：是谁、在何时修建了它
What they can't agree on is who built it and when.
一位专家告诉我  具有阿芝台克文化的遗留特征
One expert tells me this has features reminiscent of the Aztecs.
另一位却说很可能是柬埔寨风格
Another tells me it's probably Cambodian.
他们达成共识的是
What they all agree on is that
平滑的侧面一定是埃及风格
the smooth side is definitively Egyptian.
我认为你的专家们说得不错
- I think your experts are right.
-哪一位? -都说得不错
- Which one? - All of them.
确切点  好吗?
- Meaning what, exactly?
这座金字塔包含了这三种文化的特征
This pyramid contains the features of all three cultures.
这或许是有史以来的第一座金字塔
This might be the first pyramid ever built.
但是由谁建造的呢?
- But built by whom?
最初的文明
- By the first civilisation.
谢谢
Thank you.
但是谁能把金字塔建造在这儿呢?
But how could anyone possibly build a pyramid out here?
古代地图显示南极洲不曾为冰川覆盖
Ancient maps show Antarctica free of ice.
很可能这片大陆曾经适合居住
- It's likely the continent was once habitable.
我无法告诉你是谁建造了它
- I can't tell you who built it.
但如果我能取样  便能知道它建造的时间
But if I could take a sample from it, I can tell you how old it is.
米勒博士  我答应送你过去
Dr Miller, I'm offering to put you right next to this thing.
呃…是什么导致了热量激增呢?
- What caused the heat bloom?
不知道
- I don't know.
这块冰川的确切地点在哪儿?
- Where exactly on the ice is this?
布维岛
- Bouvetoya Island.
但不在冰面上  在冰川下2000英尺处
But it's not on the ice. It's 2,000ft below it.
奎因先生?
- Mr Quinn?
斯塔福德先生  你眼前是世界上最好的钻探队
- Mr Stafford. You're looking at the best drilling team in the world.
我们七天就能到达那个深度
We'll chew to that depth in seven days.
所有人在此训练的同时  三周内要达到熟练
Add three weeks on top of that to train everyone here.
我们没那么多时间  伍兹小姐
We don't have that kind of time, Ms Woods.
不只是我拥有南极洲上空的卫星
I'm not the only one with a satellite over Antarctica.
不久  其他人都会纷至沓来
Others will be here soon.
或许是我未表达清楚
Maybe I wasn't clear.
在此的所有人都还没准备好这次行程
No one in this room is ready for this trip.
这也是我召集你们来这儿的原因所在
That's why I asked you here.
布维岛是个与世隔绝的地方
Bouvetoya is one of the world's most isolated places.
最近的陆地也在1000英里以外
The nearest land is 1,000 miles away.
要是遇上麻烦  我们无法得到救援
- There's no help if we run into trouble.
说得不错  那是片人迹罕至的土壤
- You're right. It's a no-man's-land.
但是情况紧急  箭已离弦
But the train has left the station.
我认为我的讲话代表了船上所有人的意志
And I think I speak for everyone aboard this ship.
冒险是值得的
This is worth the risk.
另觅向导吧
Find another guide.
我和韦兰德先生谈过了  钱已经划入了你的账户
I've spoken with Mr Weyland. Money's been wired to your account.
直升机在补充燃料  准备送你回家
Chopper's refuelling to fly you home.
你们找的谁?
Who'd you get?
杰拉德·默多克
Gerald Murdoch.
进来
- Come in.
默多克只有两季的冰上作业经验  他尚未准备好
- Murdoch has two seasons of ice time. He's not ready.
别担心
- Don't worry about it.
保罗·伍德曼怎么样?
- What about Paul Woodman?
我们和他通了电话
- We called him. - And?
他和你一样  说了堆“废话”
- He gave the same bullshit answer you did.
“废话”?
"Bullshit"?
韦兰德先生  我给你讲的话怎么是废话?
What I told you in there wasn't bullshit.
要是你匆忙行事  有人会受伤
If you rush this, people will get hurt.
或许还会出人命
Maybe die.
我不明白你  我们又不是叫你带我们上珠穆朗玛峰
I don't understand. We're not asking you to take us up Everest.
我们只需要下船后  你带我们去金字塔
We need you to take us from the ship to the pyramid,
然后回来  仅此而已
and back. That's it.
到了金字塔里面  又怎么办呢?
- What about inside the pyramid?
这点不用担心
- Don't worry about that.
我们一旦抵达那里
Once we're on the site,
我们会用钱买来最好的技术和专家
we have the best technology and experts that money can buy.
-这是新的吗? -是最新的
- Is this new? - It's the latest.
韦兰德先生  要是我领队  我就绝不会离开我的队伍
Mr Weyland, when I lead my team I don't ever leave my team.
我很欣赏你的热情
I admire your passion.
我希望你和我们同行
I wish you were going with us.
你犯了个大错
You're making a mistake.
这是高层大气产生的现象
It's in the upper atmosphere.
来自太阳的质子流和电子流
Streams of protons and electrons from the sun
被地球的磁场偏折  产生了太阳辐射风暴
being deflected by the earth's magnetic field, causing a solar radiation storm.
沙尔克顿称南极洲为“人类的终极旅程”
Shackleton called Antarctica "the last great journey left to man".
这是世界上唯一一块无人知晓的地域
It's the one place left in the world that no one owns.
这儿能获得完全的自由
It's completely free.
我呢
Me,
我有点偏爱企鹅
I'm sort of partial to the penguins.
我希望你能在仔细考虑一下与我们同行  艾里莎
I wish you'd reconsider coming with us, Lex.
拜托  别又让我拿出我孩子们的照片
Come on, don't make me pull out pictures of my kids again.
你孩子可没那么可爱吧
Your kids aren't that cute.
我们去看看别人孩子的照片怎么样?
What if we got pictures of other people's kids?
想听我的忠告吗?
Want my advice?
呆在船上
Stay on the boat.
好
OK.
我来问问你
Let me ask you something.
我们和你呆在一起生还的机会大
Do we stand a better chance of surviving with you
还是和那个二流向导呆一起生还的机会大?
or with the number-two choice?
伍兹小姐  你的直升机补充好燃料了
Miss Woods, your helicopter's refuelled.
他们等着你
They're waiting for you.
大家都听着
Everybody, listen up!
都过来
Gather round.
告诉你她会留下来
Told you she'd stay.
她无法抵挡我的生物磁性
She can't resist my animal magnetism.
笑吧  米勒  笑啊
Laugh it up, Miller. Laugh it up.
各位先生?
Gentlemen?
确保你们在这次旅程中生还是我的职责
It is my job to keep you alive on this expedition,
并且需要你们的协助
and I need your help to do that.
既然我没有时间让你们得到充分训练
Since I don't have time to properly train you,
我定下三条规定
I'm laying down three rules.
第一  谁都不能单独去任何地方
One. No one goes anywhere alone.
绝不允许
Ever.
第二
Two:
所有人都必须随时保持联络
Everyone must maintain constant communication.
第三
Three:
意外将会随时发生
Unexpected things are gonna happen. When they do ...
一旦发生  谁也不要争当英雄
no one tries to be a hero.
明白吗?
Understood?
-明白  小姐 -很好
- Yes, ma'am. - Good.
经历了七季的冰上作业  我都没见到枪能挽救人的生命
Seven seasons on the ice and I've never seen a gun save someone's life.
-我并不打算用它 -那为什么还带呢?
- I don't plan on using it.  - Then why bring it?
这和常备避孕套的原理一样
Same principle as a condom.
我宁可带着不用
I'd rather have one and not need it
也不愿需要时发现没有
than need it and not have one.
很高兴你决定留下来
I'm glad that you decided to stay.
把卡车拖到冰上去
Move the trucks out on the ice.
-为什么戴个瓶盖?
- What's with the bottle cap?
-什么?
What?
什么要戴个瓶盖?
What's with the bottle cap?
这是颇有价值的考古发现
This is a valuable archaeological find.
我还是个小孩  在意大利的时候
When I was a kid growing up in Italy,
你知道这么大的月亮被称为什么吗?
you know what they call a moon that big?
罐闷月神
La luna del cacciatore.
不错
Brava.
什么意思?
- What's that?
猎月「注：收获月后的第一次满月」
- Hunter's moon.
猎月
Hunter's moon.
停  伙计们
Hold it, guys.
别熄火
- Keep those engines running!
下车
- Set it down.
再让让  康纳斯
Move over a little further. Connors.
是座废弃的捕鲸站
It's an abandoned whaling station.
好了  调上来  快点…
All right, bring it up. Come on.
根据你的卫星图像  金字塔就位于正下方
According to your satellite imagery, the pyramid is located directly beneath it.
好了  调上来  快点…展开
All right, bring it up. Come on. Spread out.
我们将在这儿扎营
We'll use this place as a base camp.
奎因先生  尽快开始钻探
Mr Quinn, begin drilling operations as soon as you can.
我就去部署
I'm on it.
好了  伙计们  开始行动
OK, guys, let's move out.
这些是什么?
- What are these?
鲸的骨头
- Whale bones.
这个工作站1904被遗弃的  一夜之间所有人都失踪了
This station was abandoned in 1904.Everyone just disappeared overnight.
自那以来一直是个谜
It was a big mystery back then.
为《国家地理》杂志来一张
One for National Geographic.
艾里莎
- Lex.
所有人都不得单独行动
- No one goes anywhere alone.
那儿有东西  听  听
There's something there. Listen. Listen.
当心点  会咬人的
Careful. They bite.
-过来  过来 -什么?
Over here. Over here. What is it?
相信吗?
Can you believe that?
完美地按照30度角钻的洞
It's drilled at a perfect 30-degree angle.
有多深?
- How far does it go down?
一直抵达金字塔
- All the way to the pyramid.
就这个  一清二楚
There it is. Clear as day.
昨天的同一时刻…
And the same time yesterday...
却什么都没有
- Nothing.
怎么挖成的?
- How was it done?
某种热力设备
- Thermal equipment of some kind.
就像你的那种?
- Like yours?
更加先进
More advanced.
强劲得难以置信
Incredibly powerful.
我从未见过这样的
I've never seen anything like it.
告诉你吧  世界上没有哪个工作组有这种机器
There's no team and no machine in the world
24小时内能钻到这个深度
that could cut to this depth in 24 hours.
好了  我们要探明此事的
Well, the only way we're gonna know for sure
唯一途径就是下去看个究竟
is to get down there and find out.
看看那个  去换了  就现在
Look at that. Change it. Now!
好了  伙计们  怎么这么久?
OK, guys, what's taking so long?
风暴就要来了
There's a storm coming.
探险队可不容生病
There's no room for sick men on this expedition.
医生告诉我  最糟糕的情况已经过去了
- My doctors tell me the worst is behind me.
你不太会撒谎啊  韦兰德先生
- You're not a very good liar, Mr Weyland.
留在船上吧  我们每个小时都向你汇报
Stay on the ship. We'll update you at the top of every hour.
生病的时候
When you get sick,
你会回想你的人生  以及如何被后人评价
you think about your life and how you're gonna be remembered.
你知道我死了会怎样吗?
You know what will happen when I go?
股价会下挫十个百分点
Ten per cent fall in share prices. Maybe twelve.
或许是12个  就这样
That's it.
我曾听过这种说法
I've heard this speech before.
我老爸在离瑞尼火山峰700英尺处跌断了腿
My dad broke his leg 700ft from the summit of Mount Rainier.
他很像你  他不肯回头  也不听我们的劝阻
He was like you.He wouldn't go back or let us stop.
我们抵达了山顶  他启开了一瓶香槟
We reached the top, and he opened a bottle of champagne.
我第一次喝酒  在14000英尺的地方和老爸一起
I had my first drink with my dad at 14,400ft.
下山途中  他腿上的血块进入了内脏
On the way down, he developed a blood clot in his leg that travelled to his lung.
他忍受了四个小时的痛苦  在离基地仅有20分钟路程的地方去世
He suffered for four hours before dying 20 minutes from the base.
你认为那是你老爸记得的最后的东西?
You think that's the last thing your dad remembers?
那种痛苦呢?
The pain?
还是和女儿一起在14000的海拔喝香槟呢?
Or drinking champagne with his daughter 14,000ft in the air?
我需要这个
I need this.
该死
Shit.
韦兰德先生
Mr Weyland!
有人滑下去了
Man down!
抓住他
Get him!
Somebody get him!
行动 就现在
Move it! Now!
我不太明白
I don't understand it.
没有设备
No equipment.
以及其他工作队的迹象
No sign of another team.
呃  那条隧道不可能自然生成
Well, that tunnel didn't dig itself.
快
Move it.
康纳斯  打开那盏灯
Connors, get those lights up.
有电了
We have power.
恭喜  韦兰德先生
Congratulations, Mr Weyland.
好像你会名垂青史了
Looks like you'll be leaving your mark after all.
谢谢
Thank you.
感谢你们
为此我要感谢你们
Thank you all for this.
我们创造历史吧
Let's make history.
托马斯
Thomas.
什么?
What is it?
我认识这是埃及人…
- I recognise the Egyptian...
第二个符号是阿芝台克人的
- The second symbol is Aztec.
英国被征服前的时代的
Pre-conquest era.
第三个是柬埔寨的
The third is Cambodian.
那你说得没错
Then you were right.
金字塔包含了三种文化
The pyramid contains all three cultures.
和它的外形一样
- That's what it looks like.
"你可以选择进入"
- "You may......choose......to enter."
“选中的人可以进入”
"Those who choose may enter."
谁教你翻译的?
Who taught you to translate?
有趣  好像就是你啊
Funny. Kinda looked like you.
呃  不是“选中”
Well, it's not "choose".
是“被选中的”
It's "chosen".
“只有被选中的人能进入”
"Only the chosen ones may enter."
奎因  是你在那儿吗?
Quinn, is that you out there?
米其尔
Mikkel.
这都是些什么?
What is all this?
是牺牲者的墓室
This is the sacrificial chamber.
可能都是阿芝台克人和埃及人
Like the Aztecs and the Egyptians.
建造这座金字塔的人都信仰宗教献祭
Whoever built this pyramid believed in ritual sacrifice.
这就是被选中的人为上帝献祭的地方
This is where the chosen ones were offered to the gods.
那些被选中的人就躺在这儿
Those that were chosen would lie here.
他们没有以任何形式被捆绑
They weren't bound or tied in any way.
他们是自愿死亡的
They went to die willingly.
男人和女人
Men and women.
这被看作一种荣誉
It was considered an honour.
幸运的人
Lucky them.
哦  上帝啊
Oh, god.
难以置信
It's incredible.
整个头骨和脊柱被整块切下来了
The entire skull and spinal column were removed in one piece.
看这个
Look at this.
这里  平整光滑的切痕
Look at them. The cleanness of the cut. Straight through the bone.
没有任何磨损  什么也没有
There's no abrasions, nothing.
可能只是风吹过这地道
It's probably just the wind, moving through the tunnels.
到这里来
Come here.
不管它是什么  已经死了很久了
Whatever this is, it's been dead awhile.
骨头已经完全钙化了
The bones have completely calcified.
完全不知道它已经有多久了
No idea how long it's been here but...
但是这里气温使它保存了下来
the temperature has kept it preserved.
它看起来像某种蝎子
It looks like some kind of scorpion.
不对  这里的气候对蝎子非常不利
No, climate is too hostile for a scorpion
你见过像这个的东西么?
Have you seen anything like it?
"他们献出生命  猎杀得以开始"
"They gave their lives so the hunt could begin."
这儿是怎么回事儿?
What happened here?
献祭中取走献身者的心脏的情况  是很普遍的
It's common in ritual sacrifice to take the heart of the victim.
很好
That's nice.
但那却不是心脏长的地方
But that's not where your heart is.
此外  看起来好像骨头被硬生生弯折了
Besides, it looks like the bones were bent straight out.
有东西从身体里钻了出来
Something broke out of this body.
你发现了什么  马克思?
- What have you found, Max?
一个通向另一层的通道
- It's a shaft to another level.
好像下面还有另外的房间
Looks like there's another room down there.
我们去下面的房间
- Let's move to that lower room.
我们走
- We're moving on, everyone.
伍兹小姐
Ms Woods.
你  留在这儿
You.
卢梭  你和他一道  带领一队人
Stay here. Rousseau, you stay with him. Keep a team with you.
清点一下所有东西
Catalogue everything.
教授
Professor.
这儿应该是献祭墓室的正下方
This should be directly below the sacrificial chamber.
塞巴斯提安
Sebastian.
一具石棺
It's a sarcophagus.
这是玛雅人长历法
This is the Long Count.
这是阿芝台克人的日历
This is the Aztec calendar.
这个  是种密码锁
And this...it's some kind of combination lock.
“日”
Days.
“月”
Months.
“年”
Years.
历盘被设置在…
The dials are set for...
1904年
1904.
有人在100年前开启过?
Someone opened this 100 years ago?
-今天几号? -十月十日
- What's today's date? - October 10.
2004年10月10日
10/10/2004.
-你确信会起作用? -不清楚
- Are you sure this is gonna work? - I don't know.
退后
Back up!
噢  上帝
Oh, my God.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
这些是什么?
- Any idea what these are?
不知道
No.
你呢?
You?
不知道
No.
我们带了专家来  是件好事情
- It's a good thing we brought the experts.
呃  不错  是件好事
- Well, yeah. It is a good thing.
因为这就像发现了摩西的DVD收藏品
Cos this is like finding Moses' DVD collection.
韦兰德?
Weyland?
有点太兴奋了
A little too much excitement.
今天我们在外面呆得足够久了
We've been out long enough for today. We'll set up
我们要回捕鲸站去扎营  明天一大早再过来
base camp at the whaling station and get back at it tomorrow morning.
呃  伍兹小姐  你可以回营地去  但我们要留在这儿
Well, you can go back to the base camp, Ms Woods, but we're staying here.
不行
No.
没有作必要的准备  你就要求动身  我们照做了
You wanted to leave without proper prep. We did.
你想作到这儿的第一批人  我们现在已经是了
You wanted to be the first here. We are.
你已经宣告了这些发现  都是你的了
You've claimed the find. It's yours.
我们一直统一行动  这些天我们必须做到
Now, we move as a team, and we're done for the day.
你听到她说的话了
You heard her.
你想如何处置这些?
- What do you wanna do with these?
带走
Take them.
我们到地面上还要进一步测试
We'll run further tests on the surface.
不  不
No. No!
别碰
Don't touch them.
小心
- Watch out!
门关了
- The doors!
- The door!
-你没事儿吧? -没事儿
- You OK? - Yeah.
石板大概有两吨重
Slab's gotta weigh two tons.
我们没办法弄开它
We'll never move it.
你说这间房间叫什么来着?
What did you say this room was called?
献祭墓室
Sacrificial chamber.
听的见么?
Can you hear me?
-卢梭 -托米  进来
- Rousseau. - Tommy, come in.
关于这个地方的信息  你有什么没告诉我的?
- Is there anything you didn't tell me?
没有
Nothing.
我的猜测和你一样
- Your guess is as good as mine.
无论这儿是什么  我们都没做好准备
Whatever it is, we're not prepared.
我们集合剩余的队员回地表去  行动吧
We're gonna round up the rest of the team and get to the surface. Let's move!
你们干什么?
- What are you doing?
开始我的工作
- My job.
你的职责到此为止
Yours is over.
所有人安然无恙的返回轮船  我的工作才算完成
My job is over when everyone is back on the boat safely.
枪是改变不了什么的
And that gun doesn't change anything.
这个方向应该可以到达入口
This bearing should take us back to the entrance.
我们要在捕鲸站重新组队
We'll regroup at the whaling station.
托马斯怎么办?还有卢梭?
What about Thomas? Rousseau?
我们到上面再搜寻他们
- We'll find them on the way up.
马克思?
- Max?
斯通  弗海顿  殿后
Stone, Verheiden. Cover our backs.
你卫星发现的热量激增现象  现在变得有意义了
The heat bloom your satellite detected makes more sense now.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
这座精妙的建筑物需要一个能量源
A building this sophisticated requires an energy source.
我觉得那才应是你卫星发现的
I think that's what your satellite detected.
这座金字塔的能源系统开始运作了
A power plant for this pyramid firing up.
开始准备了
- Preparing.
准备?准备什么?
- Preparing? For what?
各位先生?
Gentlemen?
靠在一起
Keep close.
-认得他们肩部的东西吗? -认得
- Recognise what's on their shoulders? - Yeah.
我们崇拜这些东西?
- We worshipped these things?
据此来讲  是的
- According to this, we did.
你们从石棺里移走的古器物
And the artefacts you removed from the sarcophagus
大概就是他们的武器
seem to be their weapons.
我们继续走
Let's keep moving.
离入口只有200码了
Only another 200 yards to the entrance.
掩护
Take cover.
快
Move!
斯通哪儿去了?
Where's Stone?
斯通
Stone!
金字塔又开始移动了
The pyramid's shifting again.
门快关上了  快出去
The doors are closing. Get out!
快
Come on.
好  走
OK. Let's go.
走
Let's go.
走啊
嗨 弗海顿
Hey! Verheiden!
来人啊
Somebody!
快跑 走啊
Run! Let's go!
我打中了那个杂种
I hit that son of a bitch dead on.
它们停下来了么? 它们慢下来了么?
It didn't stop, It didn't slow.
-嗨 弗海顿  -它们走了?
- Hey, Verheiden. - It didn't even flinch!
-弗海顿 -干什么?
- Verheiden. - What?
我不是一个战士  但是我认为你真的需要冷静一下
I'm not a soldier but I think you should calm down, really.
我们还没有死  知道么?
We're not dead yet, okay?
那好  谢谢了 教授
Well, thanks, professor.
应该是“博士”… 还有  谢谢了
Actually it's 'doctor'... and you're welcome.
什么啊?
What?
嗨 能听见吗?
Hey! Can you hear me?
我是康纳斯 你们在哪儿?
It's Connors! Where are you?
我们出不去了
We're never getting out of this place.
你们有孩子吗?
Have you got any children?
有个儿子
- Got a son.
一样  我有两个
- Yeah, I've got two.
就是说我们不能放弃
That means that we do not have the luxury of quitting.
我们要离开这儿
We're gonna make it outta here.
我们要活着  即使一路上我得背着你走
We're surviving this if I have to carry you the whole way.
后面无路可走
There's no way out back there.
没有损坏
No damage.
我们死了一个人
One of our men is dead.
我需要知道他是怎么死的
I need to know what this man died for.
为了试图创造历史而死
He died trying to make history.
谁的历史?你的?
Whose... yours?
什么?
- What's that?
推测而已
- Just a theory.
阿芝台克人的历法是公制的
The Aztec calendar was metric.
基于十进制
Based on multiples of ten.
我猜这座金字塔每十分钟会变换一次
I'm guessing the pyramid reconfigures every ten minutes.
我们靠在一起
Let's stick together.
韦兰德
Weyland.
我们就像迷宫里的老鼠
It would seem that we are rats in a maze.
抱歉
Sorry.
康纳斯?康纳斯
Connors? Connors!
弗海顿?弗海顿?
Verheiden? Verheiden?
-噢  上帝 -米勒博士
- Oh, God. - Dr Miller!
救我出去
Get me outta here!
不要紧  我找路下去  好吗?
It's OK. I'm gonna find a way to get down to you. OK?
弗海顿
Verheiden!
不
No!
想吃我吗?
You want a piece of me?
你这个婊子养的丑种
You ugly son of a bitch!
噢  上帝
Oh, God.
韦兰德
Weyland.
别碰  他们只会妨碍我们
Leave it. They can only slow us down.
空手而归的话  代价就太大了
Too much has been lost to leave here with nothing.
给我
Give it to me.
马克思
Max.
挺住
Hold on.
当心
Look out!
来  我们必须找到韦兰德
Come on. We have to get Weyland.
韦兰德  过来
Weyland, come on.
他们是什么?
What were those things?
-他们是什么? -你是专家啊
- You tell me, you're the pyramid expert.
我要歇一下  我要歇一下
I've got to stop. I've got to stop.
放松  韦兰德
Take it easy. Weyland.
看着我
Weyland, look at me.
Look at me.
你必须放慢呼吸
You have to slow your breathing down.
慢慢来  稳住呼吸
Slow, steady breaths.
韦兰德  来
- Weyland, come on.
我站不起来
- I can hardly stand.
我不想你死在这下面
I'm not gonna let you die down here.
你不会这样想
You didn't.
又来了一个
- There's another one.
我们快走  快点
We have to go. Now!
-韦兰德 -跟我们走
- Weyland. - Come with us.
-带她离开这儿 -韦兰德
- Get her outta here. - Weyland.
-快  -来
- Now! - Come on.
快跑
Run!
别背对着我
Don't turn your back on me.
-等等 -这边
- Wait. - This way.
韦兰德
- Weyland.
你对付不了他们
You can't hold them.
我们得立刻跑
We have to go.
我们一起带着它去地面上
We keep it together, we make it to the surface.
我们走
Let's go. Let's go.
我们一起带着它去地面上
We keep it together, we make it to the surface.
带着它去地面上
we make it to the surface.
We make it to the surface.
-等等 -这边
- Wait. - This way.
走 走
Go! Go!
往这儿看
Look over here.
他在身上作记号
- He's marking himself.
什么?
What?
古代的勇士会用他们捕杀的猎物的血来标志自己
Ancient warriors would mark themselves with the blood of their kill.
这是种仪式
It's a rite of passage.
开始明白了
This is starting to make sense.
我认为这是一个成人仪式
I think this is a manhood ritual.
他们被送来这里  证明自己有能力成为成人
They've been sent here to prove that they are worthy to become adults.
你说他们是什么…
You're saying they're what...
少年?
teenagers?
这就是为什么他们一开始没有携带那些枪炮的原因
That's why they didn't carry those guns with them to begin with.
他们必须去获得武器
They have to earn them.
这些象形文字解读起来有点困难
The hieroglyphs are a little difficult to make out.
但故事都记载于此
But the story is all here.
几千年前
Thousands of years ago,
这些猎人发现了这颗文明停滞不前的行星
these hunters found a backwater planet.
他们教人类如何建造
They taught humans how to build
因此被奉为神
and were worshipped as gods.
每隔百年  神会返回一次
Every hundred years the gods would return.
返回的时候
And when they did,
他们期待一次献祭
they would expect a sacrifice.
人类被用于繁殖这类终极掠食者
Humans were used to breed the ultimate prey.
猎人们和这些巨蛇作战
The hunters would battle with these great serpents
以此证明他们配带此标志
to prove themselves worthy to carry the mark.
但如果猎人输了
But if the hunters lost,
他们会让一切灰飞烟灭
they made sure nothing survived.
整个文明一夜之间消失
An entire civilisation wiped out overnight.
这么说来… 具有人类特质的猎人
So... the humanoids, the hunters -
——他们  派这些生物到此  是为了狩猎?
they brought those creatures here to hunt?
他们把我们当成牲畜
And they use us like cattle.
我们是他们繁衍的宿主
We're hosts for them to breed in.
热量激增便是引诱我们来此的信号
The heat bloom was the sign to lure us down here.
整个就是一个圈套
This whole thing was a trap.
没有我们
Without us,
他们可能就无法狩猎
there could be no hunt.
弗海顿
Verheiden!
噢  该死
Oh, shit.
那扇门开的时候
When that door opens,
我们就会死亡
we're dead.
如果我们改变了状况  就不会死亡
- Not if we set things right.
你的意思是?
- What do you mean?
这座金字塔就像是监狱
This pyramid is like a prison.
我们拿走了卫兵的枪
We took the guards' guns,
所以囚犯就肆意妄为
and now the prisoners are running free.
要重建秩序  卫兵就必须要得到他们的枪
To restore order, the guards need their guns.
门开的时候
When that door opens,
我们就把他的枪放回原位
we're gonna give that thing his gun back.
你疯了?
Are you crazy?
狩猎时  被猎杀的动物绝不会为猎人装配武器
During a big-game hunt, the animals being hunted don't arm the hunters.
他们不是来猎杀我们的
They're not hunting us.
我们介乎战争双方之间
We're in the middle of a war.
-这时候应该选择依靠一方 -我们自己是一方
- It's time to pick a side. - We are on our side.
我们必须考虑一下无法活着出去的可能性
We have to consider the possibility that we might not make it out of here.
但我们也要确保那些巨蛇不会到达地表
But we have to make sure those serpents don't reach the surface.
因为一旦他们到了
Because if they do,
万事万物将不复存在
everything everywhere could die.
敌人的敌人…
The enemy of my enemy...
就是朋友
is my friend.
我们去找我们的朋友吧
Let's go find our friend.
意大利语“极度恐惧”怎么讲?
How do you say "scared shitless" in Italian?
差不多就这样
More or less.
艾里莎
Lex.
抓住了
Hold on.
来  艾里莎
Come on, Lex.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait.
拜托  等等
Please, wait.
敌人的敌人就是朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
我和你一起  听到了吗?你个丑陋的怪物?
I'm coming with you. You hear me, you ugly creature?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
米勒
Miller!
塞巴斯提安
Sebastian.
救我  艾里莎
- Help me, Lex.
我救你出去
- I'm gonna get you out of there.
太晚了
- It's too late.
-它在我身体里 -我来救你出去
It's inside me. - I'm gonna get you outta here.
你不能…
- You can't...
不  不  不 不
No. No. No! No!
我得去救他
I have to help him.
艾里莎
Lex!
他们绝不能去地表
They mustn't reach the surface.
他们绝不能抵达地表
我知道
I know.
快开枪
Do it!
抱歉  抱歉
I'm sorry.
是颗炸弹
It's a bomb.
呃  真希望能把这该死的东西都炸死
Well, I hope it kills every fucking one of 'em.
你真是个丑陋的母亲…
You are one ugly mother...
好了
Got it!